Sangwon Seo

\$\left(832) 839-3228 | Sangwon.seo@rice.edu | \$\textit{\alpha}\$ sangwonseo.com in sangwon91 | 🔰 SangwonSeo_ | 🎓 Google Scholar

About Me

My research centers on Human Behavior Modeling, Human-Robot Collaboration, and Human-Centered AI. During my PhD, I developed imitation/reinforcement learning algorithms that can learn more general agent policies from diverse human behaviors, and an AI-based coaching algorithm that improves human-human and human-robot(AI) teamwork. I have published multiple papers as a lead author at top AI venues.

I have strong programming skills, developed through my experience as a software engineer at a medical AI startup before starting my PhD. There, I spent over three years building commercial software for 3D medical image modeling. I prioritize code maintainability and unit testing for reproducibility. Although these practices may slow down initial development, I believe they ultimately lead to faster progress in the long run.

Education

Rice University, Houston, TX

Aug 2019 - Present

Ph.D. in Computer Science

Thesis (Tentative): AI-Assisted Teamwork

Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

Mar 2013 - Feb 2015

M.S in Bioengineering

• Thesis: Performance Enhancement in Heart Rate Variability Analysis with Constrained Missing RR Interval Estimation

Seoul National University, Seoul, South Korea

Mar 2009 – Feb 2013

B.S. in Electrical and Computer Engineering

• Thesis: Multiplexing of Bead-Based Immunoassays using a BioMEMS

Experience

Honda Research Institute USA, San Jose, CA

May 2024 - Aug 2024

Research Intern

- · Job Description: Human behavior modeling and optimization for human-aware automation
- Developed mathematical models to capture changes in human propensities for interacting with other agents and learned these models from demonstrations.
- Inferred individual interaction propensities with other agents from observable states and actions using seguential Monte Carlo methods

Human-Centered AI and Robotics Group, Rice University, Houston, TX Aug 2020 – Present

Ph.D. Candidate (Advisor: Prof. Vaibhav Unhelkar)

- Proposed a team coaching AI algorithm to improve teamwork in real time during tasks
- Developed sample- and label-efficient imitation learning algorithms to learn a generative model of team behavior
- Developed a hierarchical imitation learning algorithm to learn the intentional behavior of experts from demonstrations
- Implemented multiple teamwork simulators and research tools
- · Implemented a web-based interactive experiment framework and conducted human subject experi-

Coreline Soft, Seoul, South Korea

Apr 2016 - Jun 2019

Associate Research Engineer

- Responsible for developing algorithms for AVIEW MODELER, a medical 3D printing solution
- Developed geometric modeling and processing algorithms
- Implemented a volume and surface rendering pipeline

Agency for Defense Development, Daejeon, South Korea

Mar 2015 - Mar 2016

Researcher

Developed a telemetry system for aircraft

Biomedical Signal and Information Lab, Seoul National University M.S Student (Advisor: Prof. Kwang Suk Park)

Feb 2013 - Feb 2015

- Developed signal/image processing algorithms for daily monitoring of physiological signals
- Developed autoregressive moving average-based interpolation methods to enhance heart rate variability analysis corrupted with missing measurements
- * My employment at the Agency for Defense Development and Coreline Soft is recognized as fulfilling the military service in South Korea.

Publications

- S. Seo and V. V. Unhelkar, "IDIL: Imitation Learning of Intent-Driven Expert Behavior", 23nd International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS), 2024 (Acceptance rate 25%)
- S. Seo, "AI-Assisted Human Teamwork", AAAI-24 Doctoral Consortium, 2024
- S. Seo, B. Han and V. V. Unhelkar, "Automated Task-Time Interventions to Improve Teamwork using Imitation Learning", 22nd International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS), 2023 (Acceptance rate 23.3%)
- **S. Seo** and V. V. Unhelkar, "Semi-Supervised Imitation Learning of Team Policies from Suboptimal Demonstrations", *31st International Joint Conference on Artificial Intelligence (IJCAI)*, 2022 (Acceptance rate 14.9%)
- S. Seo, L. R. Kennedy-Metz, M. A. Zenati, J. A. Shah, R. D. Dias and V. V. Unhelkar, "Towards an AI coach to infer team mental model alignment in healthcare", 2021 IEEE Conference on Cognitive and Computational Aspects of Situation Management (CogSIMA), pp. 39-44, 2021
- S. Kwon, D. Lee, J. Kim, Y. Lee, S. Kang, **S. Seo** and K. Park, "Sinabro: A smartphone-integrated opportunistic electrocardiogram monitoring system", *Sensors*, 16(3), p.361, 2016
- S. H. Hwang, S. Seo, H. N. Yoon, H. J. Baek, J. Cho, J. W. Choi, Y. J. Lee, D.-U. Jeong and K. Park, "Sleep period time estimation based on electrodermal activity", *IEEE journal of biomedical and health informatics (J-BHI)*, 21(1), pp.115-122, 2015
- S. Kang, S. Kwon, C. Yoo, S. Seo, K. Park, J. Song and Y. Lee, "Sinabro: Opportunistic and unobtrusive mobile electrocardiogram monitoring system", 15th Workshop on Mobile Computing Systems and Applications (HotMobile), pp. 1-6, 2014
- J. Kim, S. Kwon, S. Seo and K. Park, "Highly wearable galvanic skin response sensor using flexible and conductive polymer foam", 36th annual international conference of the IEEE engineering in medicine and biology society (EMBC), pp. 6631-6634, 2014

Working / Under-review Papers

- **S. Seo** and V. V. Unhelkar, "Imitation Learning of Diverse Team Behavior from Heterogeneous Demonstrations", *Under Review*
- **S. Seo**, B. Han, R. E. Harari, R. D. Dias, M. A. Zenati, E. Salas and V. V. Unhelkar, "Socratic: Enhancing Human Teamwork via AI-enabled Coaching", *Under Review*
- Z. Qian, S. Seo, and V. V. Unhelkar, "Learning Human Preferences for Agent Behavior using Demonstrations and Large Language Models"

Honors & Awards

National Scholarship for Science and Engineering, Korea Student Aid Foundation

Mar 2009

Teaching Experience

Teaching Assistant

COMP 646: Deep Learning for Vision and Language (Prof. Vicente Ordóñez-Román) Spring 2023 COMP 440/557: Artificial Intelligence (Prof. Devika Subramanian) Fall 2021

Advising & Mentoring

Arnav Adhikari, Highschool Student, Houston, TXMay 2023 - Dec 2023Bing (Tim) Han, Undergraduate Student, Rice UniversityMay 2022 - May 2024Zhanyi Sun, Undergraduate Student, Rice UniversityJan 2022 - Jun 2022

Reviewer ____

International Conference on Autonomous Agents and Multiagent Systems (AAMAS) International Conference on Advanced Robotics and Its Social Impacts (ARSO) Robotics and Automation Letters (RA-L) International Conference on Robotics and Automation (ICRA)

Skills

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES Python | C | C++ | Javascript | HTML | SQL | Matlab | LaTeX

FRAMEWORKS & LIBRARIES OpenGL | OpenMP | Flask | Gym | PyTorch | Tensorflow | WandB

SOFTWARE DEVELOPMENT Git | Docker | CMake | VSCode | Jupyter

ROBOT DEVELOPMENT Motion Capture (OptiTrack) | ROS | MoveIt | OMPL

LANGUAGES English | Korean

Extra

AAMAS Student Volunteer	2023
Student Venture Network, Seoul National University	Mar 2012 – July 2012
College of Engineering Tennis Club, Seoul National University	Mar 2010 – Feb 2013
System Administrator, ECE Department, Seoul National University	Mar 2010 – Feb 2011
SNU Mentoring, Seoul National University	Sep 2009 – Feb 2010